<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Towards a More Secure SOHO Router</title>
    <link>http://securerouter.net/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Towards a More Secure SOHO Router</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 19:09:14 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://securerouter.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>first post welcome</title>
      <link>http://securerouter.net/blog/first-post-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 19:09:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://securerouter.net/blog/first-post-welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this blog is to explore existing and developing technologies to keep small (consumer grade) Internet devices more secure. Everyone knows Internet security is a big problem, and large corporate enterprises have expensive options available to them that aren&amp;rsquo;t available to the average consumer. Even if they were available at consumer price points, they are designed to be configured and operated by teams of skilled network engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think better can be done!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About The Secure Router Blog Project</title>
      <link>http://securerouter.net/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 18:53:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://securerouter.net/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Internet security is terrible. Everybody knows this. Internet security for consumer devices is worse - usually &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; worse than more expensive devices designed for large corporate enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be true forever. We can have better security for consumer devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The router has a &lt;em&gt;privileged position&lt;/em&gt; on the small office or home office network. Not only is it a networked device, all other network traffic passes through it. This means it can strengthen or weaken the security of other devices attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is intended to be an exploration of the existing options, and possibilities for a more secure consumer home / small office router.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>